

| in | www.linkedin.com/in/alp-oran |
|----|------------------------------|
| | alporan.github.io/blog |
| | alporan@windowslive.com |
| Ö | 90 537 513 45 29 |

-

PROFILE

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of developing, testing and maintaining software systems. Quick adaptation to new challenges and responsibilities. Strong problem solving skills with an analytical mindset. Experience working as part of a productive team, as well as effectively self-manage during personal projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sekerbank T.A.Ş

Senior Software Engineer, 2020-2021

Main responsibilities;

- Developing applications for Internet and Mobile Branches by using Java, Spring Framework and Agile practices.
- Maintaining legacy JSP-Servlet based Java EE web-application.

Bilge Adam

Software Engineer, 2020-2021 Consultant for Sekerbank T.A.Ş.

Turkish Airlines

Software Engineer, 2017-2020

Main responsibilities;

- Developing mainframe applications for reservation, ticketing and DCS systems using Java technologies,
 IBM High Level Assembler and Agile practices.
- Migrating mainframe applications to the open systems as part of architectural transformation projects.
- Maintenance of code base and database records.
- Solving dumps and system errors.
- Automating manual tasks and test cases with Python Programming Language.
- Providing support for teams utilizing mainframe programs.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE, Information Technologies

Sakarya University, 2018-2019

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, Electronics and Communications Engineering

Istanbul Technical University, 2011-2015

PROJECTS

Personal Webpage

Static webpage for presenting my portfolio and blogging.

Tools: Jekyll, JavaScript, HTML, CSS **Link:** https://alporan.github.io/blog

Clinic Appointment Application

Implementing CRUD operations for simple clinic appointment application.

Tools: MySQL, Angular, Spring Boot frameworks.

Link: https://alporan.github.io/blog/clinic-appointment-app

Attachmate Extra! X-treme Macro Interface

Interface for developing utility programs and macros with Python programming language for Extra! X-treme terminals.

Tools: Python, PyQt5, Extra! X-treme API

Link: https://alporan.github.io/blog/extra-xtreme-macro-interface

Blazing Fruits

Android game checks multitasking and hand-eye coordination.

Tools: Java, Android Studio, libGDX Library

Link: https://alporan.github.io/blog/blazing fruits

An Indoor Localization Algorithm On FPGA

Multiple RF reader modules were localized by using received signal strength value from stationary RFID tags. Localization algorithm was implemented on an FPGA.

Tools: Verilog, C++, FPGAs

Link: https://web.itu.edu.tr/~orssi/thesis/2015/AlpOran bit.pdf

SKILLS

Programming Languages & Frameworks

- Java
- Spring Framework
- Spring Boot
- Jakarta EE
- IBM High-Level Assembler Language
- SQL
- Python
- Hibernate
- JUnit

Tools

- Git
- GitHub / BitBucket
- Relational Databases
- JIRA
- CA Endevor SCM
- CA Clarity PPM

LANGUAGES & TEST SCORES

Turkish: Native or bilingual proficiency **English**: Full professional proficiency

IELTS (International English Language Testing System), Nov 2015

Reading: 9/9, Listening: 8.5/9, Speaking: 7/9, Writing: 6/9

Overall Score: 7.5/9

TOEFL (Test Of English as a Foreign Language), Jul 2015

Reading: 26/30, Listening: 26/30, Speaking: 19/30, Writing: 21/30

Total Score: 92/120